Um, that is a game-changer right there.
Dang it, Joel. Why didn't you tell me
about that before, man? This is I was
thinking about it, but we had already
moved on when we talked.
We're a little light on news topics for
this week, but I do have some like, I
don't know, in the dock I have pre-topic
[__] shooting
category here and just got a bunch of
fun things to talk about. So, the first
one that I wanted to ask and I've
actually wanted to ask you this for a
couple weeks. How often do you Well,
you're you're pretty you're pretty
active in
chat, right? In some of the other hacker
chats that we're in.
Um,
do you use that more than you use social
media, do you think? And what kind of
role does hacker chats kind of play in
your social life online?
Yeah, 100%. I mean, like hacker chats
are probably like close to
90% of what I like my what I would
consider like my social circle. So, like
most like I I would say 99% of my social
circles are like online. Most of people
like people that I'm friends with and
like close closely acquainted with are
not people who I know like who like live
near me, like physically near to me. Um,
and then
day-to-day, like the majority of people
that I talk with are probably hackers
and hacker chats.
I feel like I underuse that
substantially cuz we're in like quite a
few little, you know, hacker chats that
we've got together with some of the
other hackers in our in the bug bounty
community. And like, I feel like I'm
kind of a ghost there. At least I like
I'll go in there and I'll read it from
time to time, but I'm not like
interacting quite as much. And I mean, I
don't really do that much on social
media either, but I feel like, you know,
when I'm ready to just like mindlessly
scroll, I go to social media and, you
know, scroll through Twitter or
something like that instead of like
going to the hacker chats and reading,
you know, all you guys kind of just
talking. So, I think it maybe I need to
to switch that around a little bit cuz
whenever I get in there, I see you and
the guys getting into some pretty cool
stuff and I I want to I want to get in
on that. Yeah, I I mean, I like to just
like
converse in there. So, I feel like
social media is a lot more like posty.
So, like when I'm using social media,
it's more for me to like broadcast like
publicly that I'm doing something. And
if I'm in like the hacker chats, it's
more like I'm having private
conversations with like people that I
trust.
A lot more than just like random public.
I definitely do that for like when I've
got a bug and I know someone has some
expertise, I'll like DM them in like,
you know, one of the Slack channels or
like on Discord or something. But like,
yeah, just just chilling. I think I
think that's I think that's a an
important part of the hacker community
that like, I don't know, I haven't been
I I used to be a lot more religious
about reading, you know, all the
different channels and stuff like that,
but I've just kind of fallen out of it
lately since I've been, you know,
running a little short on time with the
rental property and some other things.
So, that's something I need to work on.
it's really hard to keep up with all of
it, too. There's like a ton of messages
all the time. So, even I like sometimes
I just like I'll see like a bunch of
stuff going on. I'm like, I don't have
time to do and I'll just do it.
I feel that. Um,
solid. The The other thing I had here
was Okay, just want to do a
clarification because we did an episode
a while back, which by the way, I'm
going to call out our audience on this
one. Let me just pull up the statistics
real quick. You all said when I put a
post on Twitter about what you wanted to
see, you said that you wanted to see
exclusive techniques and tool releases.
And our Rebind Multi A tool release and
browser SSRF
like episode is like one of the worst
performing episodes out there. So, one,
you guys suck. Two,
I'm glad you didn't listen to it because
I actually made a mistake in there that
somebody messaged in to
info@criticalthinkingpodcast.io
and corrected me on.
This guy, Cyfron, shot me a shot me a
message and said, "Hey, by the way, the
DNS rebinding attack that we talked
about in that episode, which you if, you
know, if you haven't heard it, that that
bad boy's episode number nine, so go
check it out. But, I was saying that it
mostly it works for Windows only. Um,
because of the way the DNS rebinding
works, like if you're in Linux or in Mac
OS, it defaults to the private IP
address first instead of the
public IP address. But,
um, this guy, Cyfron, messaged me and
said, "Hey, just FYI,
one, the tool you made is completely
redundant because NCC Group Singularity
does the same thing." And I was like,
"Okay, you know what? Fine, but, you
know, maybe there are some features in
there that I have that they don't have
or vice versa or whatever. But, two, um,
we can actually you can use this attack
to hit localhost-ish on
Linux and Mac OS by hitting 0.0.0.0."
Interesting. Yeah, so that's pretty
cool. I mean, it's it's it's
not necessarily something that, you
know, is going to get you access to an
internal um, piece there, but it's
better than nothing. So, definitely
check that out. Um, set as the target
for that rebind
0.0.0.0 and you might be able to hit
some internal um, APIs or something like
that if it's sitting behind a reverse
proxy.
Mm, super interesting. It's It's very
interesting behavior that it would
default to like from going to 0.0.0.0 to
localhost.
exactly. And you know, you'd think with
with Linux and Mac OS, you know,
by default checking to see if they have,
you know, a private IP address in that
DNS resolution, they would also think
about 0.0.0.0, but I guess they're not
thinking about the reverse proxy sort of
situation. Yeah, that's super super
interesting.
Okay. Dude, the other thing I want to
talk about this guy, the Flipper. Oh,
yeah, one of these? Yeah, you
Are you serious? You had it sitting
right in
your desk right in front of you, too?
Yeah, the Flipper.
Um, have you set this thing up yet?
Yeah, man. I've got my I have a custom
firmware on mine.
Okay. Okay, Joel. All right. Fine. Um, I
just got mine a while back and I haven't
had the chance to play around with it
yet, but I feel like this could be
helpful for the live hacking event that
we're doing starting soon. Um, so I'm
going to get Bringing mine. Yeah, I'm
going to get some firmware on this guy.
And and hopefully we'll be able to
report back how exactly it's working
hitting some Bluetooth protocols. And
yeah, it's pretty much only going to be
Bluetooth, I think, for this this event
that we're going to go after.
Yeah, I mean, I would be surprised if
it's doing other stuff, especially in
like the ranges that the Flipper is
going to do like sub-gigahertz and
stuff, but it's always possible. I mean,
sometimes you'll see stuff using like
megahertz.
Yep, so that's that's definitely on the
list. The The other thing that I want to
talk about while we were on the topic of
Bluetooth was I've been playing around
in prep for this live hacking event. And
if all of you watching on YouTube over
my
right shoulder there, you can see this
giant like just HackerOne towel thrown
over a bunch of things because sitting
under there is the like absolute crap
ton of devices they sent us for this
live hacking event
that Joel and I are participating in
coming up towards the end of April. And
I realized that I had them sitting there
on that table right before this we
started recording. That may or may not
be a giant blurred out square in the
video they see.
Um, hopefully I don't like move my
shoulder and like show something I'm not
supposed to show. But,
yeah, I've been playing So, one of the
one of the devices that we're targeting
sort of has a Bluetooth low energy
interface. I've never done any non-HTTP
related hack Well, like once or twice
I've done some non-HTTP related hacking,
you know, mobile aside. And I started
playing around with the BetterCap
Bluetooth low energy module and that
thing is fire. Um, really easy to use,
really consistent. And I didn't even
have to use a I don't know if this is
just the Bluetooth chip in my laptop,
but I didn't even have to use like the
Ubertooth one or anything like that, any
external cards. Just the in, you know,
the the Bluetooth chip built into my
laptop was able to enumerate the various
services that I was going after. So,
definitely definitely check out
BetterCap's Bluetooth low energy module.
Yeah, dude, you were showing me that
yesterday and I haven't done a ton of
Bluetooth hacking, either. I do mainly
either end up on like the network side
or maybe I'll like rip a chip and
go into like the source code and stuff,
but
I had been holding off on buying like an
Ubertooth or anything like that for like
a while just because I wasn't really
sure what I needed and all that kind of
stuff. And then I saw that recently
a couple months ago they announced that
the Ubertooth one was being like
retired, basically. Yeah, just as I
bought it, of course. I had it on my
wish list for like months and months and
months and I was like, "Should I buy it?
Should I buy this?" Yeah, so I did some
other some other digging and there were
a couple people talking on Reddit and
stuff that were mentioning the kinds of
stuff that they actually end up using.
And they had said that they owned the
Ubertooth, but for the most part they
don't end up using it a ton. And the
basic impression that I got is basically
it's like a Bluetooth receiver. That's
pretty much like it. Like I don't I
don't really know what it does that is
extra than that. So, a lot of people
were
were recommending this this U100D by
Sena.
So, this is this is pretty neat. It was
like 30 bucks or something. It was
really not bad. And it's apparently it
has this crazy crazy range. Apparently
it can go up to like
I want to say like 100 m or 1,000 m or
something. It's like It's really crazy.
And I was using that yesterday with
BetterCap. Yeah. And it was working
great. I can't use it on my Mac like
through Docker or anything. For some
reason Yeah, I was going to I was
curious to see if you got that working.
Yeah, it doesn't it doesn't work with
the drivers. They they have a note in it
somewhere in the documentation that you
can't use the BLE module with like Mac
or Windows because it doesn't support
like the drivers or something like that.
I was able to get it to work on my
Windows through VirtualBox. So, if I run
it if I run it within an Ubuntu VM and I
do USB pass-through with the with the
adapter, it works. Wait, wait. So, you
Wait, you did you have
VirtualBox VirtualBox
on Windows on your Windows box? You had
Okay, for a second I thought you
I thought you had said that you were on
your Mac and then you had a Windows
virtual machine and then you had a
Ubuntu virtual machine on that.
I'm like, "So, what the freak are you
doing?"
No, I do I have a two computer I have
Yeah, I have a Mac laptop and a Windows
PC. On the Windows PC, I was running
Ubuntu within a VirtualBox VM. Okay. And
I had the Sena
Bluetooth adapter plugged in and pass
through over USB. Nice.
I actually had to compile bettercap from
source because the one from apt doesn't
have
like BLE the BLE module or whatever for
some reason. So,
What the heck? Really?
Yeah, super weird.
that, too? I don't Maybe I did that a
while back. I did compile it from a
Docker container. No, I didn't. I
actually started playing around with it
a little bit before when I was attacking
a different surface and I didn't get
very far and I had to move on to
something else. So, I might have
compiled it from source back when and
just had it installed on my laptop, but
Interesting. Yeah, I have that my laptop
runs I just dual boot Windows and and
Ubuntu and that's always worked really
well for me because like at the end of
the day, I'm running Ubuntu 99% of the
time and then you know that that other
1% of the time is when I'm not at home
and want to game. Yeah.
very very minimal very minimal time
frame.
So, yeah, that's how I just plugged it
straight into my
or actually my you know, my laptop had
had a had just a built-in Bluetooth chip
and just use that. So, that worked
great.
Yeah, I'd imagine that most of the
built-in Bluetooth chips probably can
work, but
I think it mostly has to do with the
drivers that are installed for like Mac
and Windows specifically like they
mentioned that cause those kinds of
problems. So, probably just if you have
Linux, you can just give it a shot. Like
if you have BlueZ and it picks up your
Bluetooth chip or whatever your your
Bluetooth adapter already, then you're
probably good to go. Solid.
Um Slight said we're little little
little weak on the news this week.
There's only one one little thing. I
don't know if you had anything, but the
only thing that I saw was this Burp VPS
proxy. Did you see that?
I did not. This is a I I saw that you
posted it in the doc and that was the
first that I'd heard of it. Yeah, so
it's pretty much like it's a Burp
extension
and I I should I mean the guy on
the guy that has it on on GitHub is Dev
Demond Dev. Um but somebody posted on
Twitter, too. I I should have to go find
that that tweet and give him a
shout-out, but um it looks like
my favorite type of Burp plugin where
it's just like it does something
complex, but all you have to do is just
take an API key and plug it in and then
just boom, it's done. Yeah, it's
probably like one API call. Yeah, it's
it's great cuz so, you know, what it
what it's doing is is it supports a
bunch of different providers. It It
supports AWS, DigitalOcean, Linode and
you just drop your API key in there and
it'll just spin up um a VPS proxy for
Burp and go you know, go out there, spin
it up, connect your Burp to it so you're
not constantly getting um
banned uh when you're when you're
performing some testing. So, I feel like
this is going to be really helpful when
you have one of those stupid targets
that like bans you every 2 minutes and
doesn't help you get that fixed cuz
that's ridiculous.
That's interesting. So, it's just for
proxying your Burp traffic? Yeah. Yeah,
it looks like it. Yep.
Uses a SOCKS5 proxy.
Okay, very interesting. There is um
there's this other This reminds me of a
similar tool called FireProx.
Um Yeah, but that's that's for like
that's like for all of of the That That
gives you a URL to hit, right?
I don't know. So, So, my understanding
is that basically just like uses the um
I think it uses Lambda or something to
basically just rotate your IPs so that
you're not hitting it from the same IP
for all your different requests. It's
not Lambda. What is it?
Uh it's not Lambda, you're right.
It's like IP gateway or something like
that. API gateway.
Yeah, yeah, there you go.
Yeah, we we should definitely So, it
uses API gateways to um
to basically give you different IPs for
all your requests so that you don't get
like a single IP banned. I'm not sure
how efficient it is or anything like
that, but that also might be a good
option instead of having a whole have an
entire VPS set up, you could basically
just have one of these instances and
just like hit it hit it hit it until you
get IP banned and then spin up another
instance. Yeah, this this definitely
works well if you've got something like
a a setup where one host is blocking
you, you know, specifically and then you
can just spin up a a FireProx URL for
that specific host and then hit that
instead and you'll you'll every request
will come from a different IP. Um but if
you're trying to attack, you know, a
target that has a bunch of different
like, you know, APIs that need to
interwork together and stuff like that,
then Burp VPS proxy might be better so
that all of your traffic is going
through, you know, a VPS and then you
can kind of spin it up spin it down as
you get banned along the way.
Yeah. Yeah, but we'll link to both of
those tools down below.
Yeah.
All right, that's all I had for the for
the pre pre-topic [__]
Want to want to want to dump or dump
want to dive right into it?
Let's do it, man. Let's let's get right
into it. Um so,
get some water in you, Joel, cuz you're
going to be doing some talking this
episode. We are talking about on dynamic
mobile hacking specifically with with
Frida.
Um this is sort of a a sequel to the
other mobile episode that we've got
which was episode number six.
Um
So, if you haven't seen that, feel free
to check that out. There might be some
If you haven't seen that, depending on
your mobile knowledge, you might be a
little bit lost, but all right. I'm
going to set the scene and then we'll
jump right in. So, what we talked about
last time was a lot of the basics of of
mobile stuff. We talked about all the
different components, intents,
activities, you know, just kind of
getting the our our hands dirty in
Android stuff. Um
And so, what what we kind of want to And
but that was largely focused on
understanding how Android is programmed
and how we can read the code largely
talking about static analysis. So, in
the field of mobile hacking, there's,
you know, two primary and and correct me
if if I'm missing anything here, Joel,
but you know, there's two primary
approaches. There's a static analysis
where you can you read through the code
and you try to identify vulnerabilities
that way and then there's a dynamic
analysis which is
you know, you're you're using a tool
like Frida or you're actually getting in
the app and making stuff happen
and try figuring out how the app works
that way. Um And and so, the dynamic
analysis piece is kind of what I want to
focus on today.
But, you know, these two should be used
in conjunction, right, Joel?
Right. Right. Yeah, so usually I end up
using both whenever I'm doing hacking.
Like I'll probably start with some
static analysis, but you really want to
like figure out what's going on within
the app and some of those things are way
too complex to try and figure out just
by reading source code and it's just
simpler and easier to call it directly
or look at what it's doing with Frida.
Yeah, for sure. So,
for those of us that aren't aren't
familiar with this. So,
dynamic analysis just give me like a
brief overview of what that looks like
and how we are able even to do that.
Yeah, so essentially dynamic analysis is
just
looking at or maybe modifying or hooking
parts of the app while it's running. So,
it's happening dynamically. It's not
based on um like you're not reading
through the source code. You might be to
figure out where you're going to set
your hooks, but outside of that, it's
like you're it's while the app is
running. Nice. So, So, the app is
running. So, we've got the app on a
phone or on an emulator, right? Which
what's your go-to in these sort of
situations?
99% of the time, emulator.
The only times I end up using a physical
device. So, like for example, with the
thing that we're working on for this
upcoming live hacking event, I will be
using a phone for at least part of it
because it uses Bluetooth to do the
setup initialization process and
right now as far as I'm aware, there's
no way to get like a functioning
Bluetooth within the emulator. The like
pass-through doesn't it doesn't work
like that.
Yeah. Um so, there's no real easy way to
do it. Maybe you could do it on Linux.
Maybe you would have a little bit of
better luck. I'm not sure. Maybe Maybe
the one the one time You see that that
phone sitting right there?
Yeah. I've already I've already got a
I've already got a a a Frida script for
you. I'll toss it over to you when you
whenever you start looking at
at stuff, but okay. So, you know, we're
using 99% of the time using an emulator.
What kind of emulator do you normally go
to? I I've got two that I'm aware of.
I've got Genymotion and then I've also
got um AVD Android virtual device thing.
The thing that comes bundled with
Android Studio. Do you use either of
those?
Yeah, so I use the one that's bundled
with Android Studio. You don't have to
get it through Android Studio. You can
download it just the Android SDK and
it's called emulator. That's like the
name of the binary.
Um and you can use it the same way. You
can call it. You can like create the
AVDs. You can do all that stuff. It's
just probably significantly easier to do
it through Android Studio mainly because
Android Studio has the stuff for
downloading and managing the SDK
packages. So, you can download like the
latest Android SDK. You can download the
Google Play image for Android O or
whatever and then you can install that
and create your emulator and configure
it. And then later on if you want to run
it just using the emulator command,
absolutely you can. Yeah, that makes
sense. I I literally every time it's so
annoying if you try to do it through
Android Studio because you have to open
Android Studio and then you've got to
click the little more options button and
then you click, you know, the Android
virtual devices, whatever, and then it
launches up this other thing. So, you've
got all these windows and if you close
any of those windows that it just closes
everything. And I'm like
I I I think it used to be a lot easier
back in the day. I think they started to
over complicate it like recently. Now,
if you run an emulator it shows like an
integrated like window within
within Android Studio. It's like it
doesn't like pop out anymore. So, if you
run just like emulator at and then like
at your like AVD or whatever, like
that's the syntax.
Um
it'll just spawn up a new window
like a like a QEMU instance and you'll
be good to go. Perfect. Yeah, I should
do that cuz I hate having all these
windows open at once and if I close any
of them then it just bloats up my
desktop. So, okay. So, you've got the
you've got the um you've got the
emulator up. So, let's say you went and
downloaded Android Studio, you've got
the AVD um open AVD AVD, select you
know, a Pixel 5, build build that guy.
Now, we're rolling um and we're
interacting with that uh virtual device
via ADB and then do you normally like
do you normally have one of those
devices that has access to the Play
Store and then just go download the APK
or do you normally like pull the APK
from somewhere and then like push it to
the device using ADB install? Yeah, so
it it depends on what I'm doing and what
the situation is.
I'd say like especially if I'm using a
physical device, yeah, I'll probably
just download the APK because
lots of times it's feature gated so you
might not even be able to download the
an APK that uses BLE if your phone
doesn't register as having BLE with the
Google Play Store. So, if you're using
some of those like Play Store downloader
tools
you might run into issues actually
trying to get that APK if you your
device doesn't have like the whatever
the compatible features. And I've just
found that you have to do it with like a
physical device if you want to get it or
you can find it online. Yeah. Yeah. I I
when I was downloading this app and and
getting installed for the for the LG
um
I I tried to install it on my main phone
and then set it up on my main phone and
then there's like some weird
incompatibility with my specific device
that I have and this version of the app
and it's if you like dig deep into the
like release notices on their their
website, it's like, "Oh, by the way, if
you have this and this, then you're just
not going to be able to use Bluetooth."
And I'm like,
I like set up that whole thing. Um
and so, yeah, that's that's a little bit
of a of a pain, but yeah, I think I
think
I had another, you know, device sitting
in my in my closet or whatever and
an old device? Yeah, it is. And
actually, so I had to update it a little
bit to get it to meet the right like APK
level or something like that and and
yeah, it was it was it
Yeah, so almost certainly the problem is
that it has Bluetooth, but it doesn't
have Bluetooth Low Energy. And so, it
has Bluetooth, but not BLE and it can't
talk with BLE stuff. I've had the same
problem with older Android devices that
I can't use for Bluetooth testing
anymore because they need BLE
specifically.
Oh, wow. Yeah. Now, this was this was an
old old device. I've just got like a
little like actually it's right here.
It's like this little it's supposed to
be like a little
you know, cable management thing. But
you just have like a little label on it
that just says 5G.
exactly Is that Is that from Is that
from GitHub?
Is it from GitHub?
Let me see.
I we definitely got it at one of the
live hacking events. I think it was.
Yeah, I think it was from GitHub.
Actually, I put it over the I have the
label over the place where I got it from
so I have no idea.
But Yeah, I think I have the same one
though. It helps to it helps to have a
bunch of, you know, old phones around
when you're doing mobile testing there
because sometimes you'll have those sort
of weird incompatibilities, right? I
just have a stack of phones in my
drawer. It's it's crazy.
Let me see your phone drawer. Um
so,
um anyway, okay. So, we've got the we've
got the app running on an emulator.
We've got um
So, then I you know, you said we're
doing this alongside with with static
analysis. So, we're opening up the app
in like So, okay. So, also, let me let
me ask.
Refresh my memory, what do you do you
with
Jad? You you unzip the APK and then you
decompile all of the the DEX files with
with Jad and then you open that up in VS
Code. Is that right? No, not even. I use
I use APK tool to extract uh basically
the decoded resources and the DEX files.
Yep. So, now you've got Smali, right?
Not not DEX. Right. And then I use Jadx
to only compile source and not not the
resources and output that into the same
folder.
So, like I feed them both the APK. So, I
feed APK tool the APK to like decompile
everything
Right.
but like not pull out Smali and all that
kind of stuff. And then I use Jadx with
the same APK to have it decompile only
the source code cuz I think Jadx also
does like resource
decoding or something, but I prefer APK
tools over that. And then
I I'll also feed Jadx APK and I'll have
it output into a fold like the same
folder and that's the source folder. So,
so Jadx Jadx, if you pass it an APK,
then it will go ahead and
It Yeah, it does DEX to JAR and
everything. Okay. Okay. Okay. I was I
was wanting to do it the Joel way when I
I did this last one. I was like, "All
right, you know what? I'm going to get
it together. I'm going to be cool. I'm
going to use VS Code like Joel and I'm
going to like, you know, have it parse
the whole thing."
you the commands that I use
and like the specific arguments and
stuff. Yeah, but I just, you know, I I
always literally I just open it all up
in Jadx GUI and and the search
functionality is kind of [__] in that
though. So, it's like,
you know, not sure if that's the right
move, but um it does get the job done
part of the time. It's especially nice
if you don't want to like have it all on
your disk, right? Like if you just want
to open a JAR file or something and you
don't want to have to have a million
Java files on your on your C drive or
whatever, then you can just use Jadx
GUI. Okay. So, the setup now is we've
got an emulator, we've got the APK
loaded onto the emulator, we've got our
source code in front of us and VS Code
or Jadx or whatever you're we're using.
And then um
now we want to start doing some dynamic
analysis. One of the most common use
cases for dynamic analysis is SSL
pinning bypass, right? So, talk to me a
little bit about how that works and then
you've got a script somewhere which I
will try to find while you're talking
that does universal bypasses, right?
Yeah, so basically cert pinning like in
a nutshell is is the device verifying
the certificate that is coming back from
the server. Okay, so if you think about
how proxying works especially for
proxying TLS or HTTP traffic, your Burp
proxy you your system has trusted that
the the CA the Burp like certificate
authority cert which is going to issue
new certificates to sign all your
different requests. And because you've
trusted it at a system level, it's fine
and you can proxy your traffic through
Burp. But if you weren't, Chrome would
throw up probably be throwing,
you know, certificate errors.
Just by default certificate pinning
settings. Yeah, exactly. Now, by default
set I guess just certificate validation,
right? This isn't necessarily pinning,
it's just normal certificate validation
over HTTPS. Yeah, this is at like a
system level. This is like normally your
system is going to check that the cert
that's signing the traffic is what it
should be and it's a valid cert and it's
not self-signed and all that kind of
stuff, right?
So,
if
by default, if you were to like install
the certificate on your Android phone,
you would probably be able to get like
some apps through there. You would run
into the same issues you would run onto
a PC if you were trying to proxy without
or with a certificate. Like for the most
part it would work, but certain apps, a
lot of apps honestly, implement this
thing called certificate pinning which
is where inside the app
Yeah, inside the app they say, "These
are the specific These are the the
specific SHA-256 or whatever
hash. This is the specific hash of the
certificate that it should be coming
back from the server. And if it doesn't
have that hash, then reject the
request." And it'll basically drop the
connection and it'll fail. You'll see it
in Burp. It'll say like, you know, TLS
verification failed or certificate
verification failed or something like
that.
And so, what you have to do is you have
to bypass that verification. You either
have to tell it that every certificate
is okay or you just have to remove that
verification step entirely.
There are a couple different like core
like HTTP libraries that are very
commonly used.
So, before we we go into that, I'm going
to try to summarize it like like I was
five here, okay? Sure. So, by default,
HTTPS is the thing that keeps our
communication with the server secure,
right? And
the way that that works is by having a
certificate presented by the server side
that says, "Hey,
I am whoever, you know, whoever they're
claiming to be." And that certificate is
signed by a certificate authority. Um
that's like the the big guy that we all
trust saying, "Hey,
you know, this guy really is this guy."
And we can validate that
cryptographically because
I'm a really smart five-year-old we're
talking to here. Um we can validate that
than a five-year-old?
No.
Um we can validate that
cryptographically
um by using uh
like cuz our our device has a set of CAs
that we we trust and we can tell whether
that signature was actually signed by
the CA versus by Joe Schmo. And so, um
that's how normal HTTPS works. Now, when
we are installing a device, you know, a
certificate or when we're trying to, you
know, see HTTPS traffic on a Android
device, we have to install Burp or
whatever intermediate proxy you're using
HTTPS certificate or their CA
certificate on our device to say, "Hey,
by the way, we also trust Burp." And
Burp just says, "Hey, I'm whoever the
heck I want to be." and just, you know,
gives you a valid certificate for every
every person, you know, coming through.
And that is how you can sort of decrypt
that traffic as
from a middle man perspective, right?
Right. And again, the main distinction
between certificate validation and like
the standard certificate validation and
certificate pinning that's happening
here is that certificate pinning says
specifically, "Only these certificates
are allowed for the traffic that I'm
trying to send." Like I'm trying to talk
to this API, I should only be getting
this certificate back or from this CA
back. And
if you're using Burp, that's not going
to be the case. So, you have to change
it at an app level, not at a system
level. You have to do both, actually.
Yeah. So, so what I just explained there
was normal certificate validation. Now,
we installed the Burp certificate on the
Android phone. There's a million
tutorials out there to do that. Now, the
phone trusts Burp, right?
Yep. And if and if um the app that we're
using relies on the phone to do this
validation, then we're Gucci.
Everything's fine. We can see the
traffic. We can decrypt the SSL. It's
it's it's perfect. But
you can test that just like go to
example.com, like HTTPS example.com, and
see if your phone throws a cert error.
Okay. So, we've got that, but then these
tricky
developers
are going to try to trip us up here by
adding an extra layer on top of that and
saying, "Okay, not only are we going to
validate the certificates, you know,
trust it at the system level or
whatever, we're also going to say that
if the certificate presented is
different than this specific
certificate." They and they put, you
know, the hash for that in the code,
then freak out and don't send any
messages, alert alert, attacker's
hacking us, right?
Okay. So, so
SSL certificate pinning.
It's a pain in the butt, man. It really
is. It it's a pain in the butt. Um so,
yeah, I'm glad we can figure out how to
get past that. Yeah. So, you mentioned
the script. I talked about this. I did
uh I did a long like interview with Ben,
um the Hamsec, and we talked about like
mobile hacking and stuff. And we also
did like a large blog post for HackerOne
about Android hacking. And in that blog
post, I linked to this Frida script at I
think at the end. Um and this is
basically my go-to script as well. Uh
that's like the same script that I use
for 99% of apps. Uh I almost never have
an issue with it unless it's a custom
implementation of cert pinning
somewhere. Um so, basically, it just
looks for a lot of the really common
certificate pinning libraries that exist
out there, okay HTTP,
um like the built-in like Android like
trust manager.
kit. Yeah, exactly. And it hooks like
all of them at as basically a lower
level as possible so that generically
speaking, it can hook most cases and it
can stop cert pinning in most cases,
including like a system level for
uh if you're using like the trusted
certs XML or whatever, like the new way
that they do it with Android. I'm
reading through the script and what
One of the things here is trusty trust
manager. Is that Is that Is that you
naming stuff or is that
Yeah, it's it's a trusty trust manager,
you
Trusty trust manager. It's very trusty.
Oh my gosh, lovely. Okay.
I don't know why that hits me so
different right now.
Trusty trust manager. All right, solid.
So, we we
we'll link that we'll link that in the
in the description.
Um definitely check out Joel's script.
And And okay, so hopefully, if they're
using one of these default, you know,
SSL pinning libraries, then you can just
run this this Frida Okay. So, we can
just run this Frida script. We're going
to explain how to do that in a second.
We'll talk a little bit about that, but
run this Frida script and then SSL
pinning should disappear and boom, you
should be able to proxy the traffic,
right?
Pretty much.
Yeah. That's That's what I've been doing
with your script for the past couple of
years and it's been great and I can
confirm that it does work.
Let's say I'll say 90% of the time, you
know, cuz there are some weird some
weird fringe ones out there, which I'll
talk about if if we get to the report
section later in this in this
conversation. I'm not sure if we will
with how long we're going right now, but
um yeah. Okay. So, now, okay, we we set
it all up, Burp certificates installed,
you know, we're seeing some traffic go
through, you know, in like our normal
Android browser or whatever, you know,
we open up the browser, we go to Google
and it it it doesn't throw a certificate
error. But when we open up the app, it
says, "Error connecting to the server."
you know, uh yeah, is what it says.
Okay. So, we've got that's a good
indicator that there's some cert pinning
there.
What's the next step?
So, if I'm trying to figure out like
custom cert pinning, for example, one of
the first places that I'll look is
So, let's say let's before we know
whether it's it's custom cert pinning or
not. I mean, do you just go right down
the rabbit hole and try to find custom
cert pinning or do you run the Frida
script in general, you know, right off
the bat? And then if it doesn't work,
then you try to go find it.
Um yeah, I mean, usually, I'll just try
it out of the box. If it doesn't work,
then I'll run my Frida script. If it
still doesn't work, then I assume it's
custom pinning.
Okay. So, so walk me through running the
Frida script. Do we just like
How does that work? Yeah, so Frida
involves basically two main parts.
There's Frida server and Frida CLI. So,
Frida CLI runs on, I'll call it the
host, that's like your laptop or your PC
or whatever, right? Where where you're
like running your scripts from and all
that kind of stuff. And then the server
runs on the device or on your emulator.
Um
So, you download Frida server from
GitHub from their releases. Uh they have
regular releases. You want to download
the one that's specifically should be
like Frida-server-
version-android-
whatever.
get wrong. So, when I'm downloading
that,
hold on, let me let me pull up that the
Frida. So, I'm going to GitHub, going to
Frida, going to releases, right? And
then they got this like list of all of
these
Yeah. And make sure you expand it. Yeah.
So, Frida
So, if I search for server,
there's there's Okay, and then there's
specifically So, it says Frida server
and then the version. And then we've got
Android x86
share your screen? Oh, yeah. Hold on,
let me see if I can
that. We have this fancy software.
way. This is nuts.
Frida
Let me see if I can find the right tab
here.
There we go.
This guy right here, right? Look at
that. We are in the next
Wow. Okay, that is so hard to read.
I don't know what I'm trying to say
there. This is This is the future. Um
This is the future.
Let me just zoom in. So, um yeah, so
we've got this, right? Frida server.
Now, we've got Frida Frida server for
Android arm, arm64, x86, x86_64,
all of these. How the heck do we know
which one to download and which one to
put on our um you know, device and it
has to be compatible with our actual um
Frida that's installed on our computer,
too, right? So, how do we determine
that? Yeah, so I always just install the
latest version of both and that will
remove any of that version confusion,
whether or not it's compatible and all
that kind of stuff. Just install the
latest version of both if if you're ever
unsure.
Uh for the architecture, it's the same
as like with Linux. So, you'd run uname
-a on on the device over ADB and it'll
tell you what the architecture of the
device is. Um if it's like AArch or if
it's uh x86 or if it's uh x86_64 or
whatever. Most of the time, you're going
to see either arms maybe titled armv7,
armv7l Okay. um armv8 EABI
or you'll see x86 or you'll see arm64.
Okay. And if And if it's on
If
you're running it in an emulator, it's
normally x86, right?
It's normally probably x86_64,
but yeah, it's going to be either x86 or
x86_64 unless you're on like an Mac M1
or M2 that has an arm chip, right? And
then it'll
Right. So,
it's going to be if you're running it on
an on an emulator, it's going to be the
same architecture as the as your CPU
unless you're explicitly emulating a
different architecture. You can run an
arm. Yeah, it's just crazy slow.
Yeah. Okay. Gotcha. So,
you go through the full step and install
Frida on your Frida command line on your
computer and Frida server on the thing
every single time. Your boy is a little
bit lazier than Joel. And so,
time. But I I usually just like have it
on the device and then if it doesn't
work, then I'll like update them both.
Okay. So,
I have some helper scripts and stuff.
But yeah,
like I mentioned, there's two steps.
There's Frida server on the device and
then the second part is Frida Frida CLI
on the computer. So, on your host,
you're going to use pip and you're going
to pip install Frida-tools and that will
install the Frida CLI on your computer
so that you can interface with the Frida
server that's running on the device.
Nice. What I always do, I'll throw this
little little tip out there, is I always
go to my command line and run
Frida--version
and then get the version and then go to
the releases and download that version
for the server and then throw that on
the device so that I don't, you know,
have any version mismatches because they
don't like that.
So, yeah, but that's probably the better
way to do it.
Yeah, so for on the device, there's a
couple like main things that you want to
be aware of.
So, the first is generally you would
want the device to be rooted.
For an emulator, you can easily root
them with this tool called root AVD.
We'll link it.
It's super great. It will basically root
the image itself so that you have SU and
all that kind of stuff. You can
get root over you can just SU to get
root on ADB and it makes everything
super easy, straightforward. Okay, so
quick question about that cuz I normally
just run ADB
What is it?
ADB root. Yeah, did I have that
automatically installed or what is that
only for images that have
Genymotion? No, I'm using I'm using AVD.
Yeah, so I think that's that's what gets
enabled when when you do that. You can
think you unless you do ADB root or
maybe you can just Well, it only does it
on some of the emulators because like on
some on the ones that have like the Play
Store Oh, yeah, yeah, that's what it is.
Okay, so you actually can root the ones
with the Play Store? Yeah, yeah. Oh,
that's what I mean. Yeah, so use root
AVD to root the Play Store images. Yeah,
so so that's a good distinction. There
are two there's like the the like
default builds. I think they're like
there's like I forget what they call it,
Google API or something and then there's
the Play Store version, right? And so
the Play Store versions have
Google Play Store services, they have
the Play Store app, they have all the
Google like built-in like
Google app services, all that kind of
stuff installed already that lets you
download apps and it's basically like
default Android. If you use just the
Google APIs one, it's like very very
bare-bones. It doesn't have Google Play
services, doesn't have the Google Play
Store, doesn't have like any of that
kind of stuff.
The problem is that a lot of apps rely
on Google Play services, so most of the
time you need that. It's really hard to
install that on just like a stock Google
API image.
They call it a production build, right?
So, if you were to run a Google Play
image like emulator image and you were
to try to do ADB root, it would say ADB
root is not enabled for production
builds and that's because they consider
the Google Play build to be a production
build. So, you have to use root AVD to
root that image so that you can have it
you can have SU access while you have
like Play Store and everything in
enabled. Otherwise, yes, you can run ADB
root and then everything you run through
ADB will be root by default. Got you.
Okay, that is that is a tidbit that I
did not know that I've struggled with in
the past because some of these things
really do require the Play Store pieces
and if you don't have root, then you
can't run Frida very easily. So then I
have to go the other route, which we'll
talk about later hopefully if we have
time, which is the
the patching the APK route. Um
But before we get down that rabbit hole,
so you know, we get root on the Android
device and then we
get Frida server on there. How do you do
you just normally just how do you how do
you get the Frida
I use ADB push.
So like you download the server on your
host on your computer and then you ADB
push the file to data local data
local  temp. That's the go-to
directory. It's a
it's a unique balance on the Android
file system because of the way that
permissions work across different
folders. It's a place where you can set
things as executable and execute them
and download stuff and you have write
permission and it's a temporary folder.
So basically some things will stay in
there, but it's used by the system for
other temp stuff that gets auto removed.
So, it's kind of a nice place. If you
read all the docs, most of the time
they'll tell you to put it there.
So push it into data local temp. You're
going to need to set it executable. So
CH mod it either I think 755 is what
they tell you to do. You can probably
plus X,
but just yeah, 755 or plus X.
And then make sure you disable SE Linux.
SE Linux is enabled by default on
Android. It's going to cause problems
with like cross-process communication
all that kind of stuff that Frida needs
to be able to do. So,
set enforce space zero. That will turn
off SE Linux and you can type get
enforce to check what your SE Linux
status is. It'll say either enforcing or
permissive. So, you want it to be
permissive. Nice. I I don't know that
I've ever done that. So maybe I think
maybe some of the other images have like
some of the images that are not the Play
Store images have it disabled by default
or something like that for debug
purposes or
I'm not sure.
Yeah, I'm not sure. Like sometimes you
run into it more than others, but it
it'll be pretty obvious when it's an SE
Linux error and you need to disable it.
Got you. Okay, so then you've got the
server running, you've got the client
running. Now, the connection
not running yet.
So, yeah, you need to run the server so
like data  data  local
temp  Frida server. The
in the newer versions of Frida, there's
a dash capital D for daemon mode that
runs it in the background automatically.
So, it used to be that you put an
ampersand after it and just do it like
that as a background process. Now, you
can just do  dash capital D and
it will run it in daemon mode. It has
that built in. And now your Frida server
is running. Now, on your host, if you
type Frida
dash LS dash devices, you should see
your Frida server like instance
basically listed there showing that it's
running, it's connected, it sees the
device, you're ready to go.
Frida dash LS dash devices.
Solid. And that's that just validates
like what what devices are connected to
to Frida. Okay, so then you've got your
server up, then you can do the fun
stuff.
Now you're ready to run the script. So,
if you're using the cert pinning script
for example, typically what I would run
is Frida dash capital U for USB which
basically tells it to use like a
plugged-in device, not the host machine
cuz you can run Frida like on processes
on your host machine. So, you want to
distinguish I want to do this on a
connected device. So, dash U for USB and
then dash L and I'll point that to my
script path dash L for load script and
then
typically dash F or dash N depending on
whether I'm attaching. So, dash F is for
spawning a new instance of an app. It'll
launch it and then attach it at the same
time versus dash N is for attaching to
an existing running instance of an app.
So, if for an example, the app crashes
on launch if Frida's attached, which
sometimes happens, then you might need
to launch the app, then attach Frida to
the running instance and you'll be good
to go. Solid. Okay, I love how you just
pulled all that out of your head. I
every single time I do this, I'm like
getting into you know, my my command
line and then I'm like typing Frida and
then I just press up up up up up up up
up.
And then and then inevitably I don't
find it and then I I resort to, you
know, when you're really desperate,
history pipe grep Frida, you know, and
then you can see the whole list.
Do you use do you use FZF fuzzy find? I
don't actually and I have I have
I have fish. I I use fish as my primary
you know, CLI
which I love I love fish, but also let
me say I a little bit regret it because
obviously the syntax is different than
bash, right? So, if you do something
like ZSH, it's it's incompatible. But
now all of my scripts that I've been
writing for the past, you know, couple
years are in fish and so if I ever try
to like switch computers into like, you
know, I I've seen, you know, we we all
I'm sure you can chat GPT that. Come on.
Yeah, oh, that's a good idea. That's a
good use for it.
Um but
yeah, you know, whenever I'm trying to
like jump onto a server and trying to
like pull down my config, you know, none
of my scripts work by default cuz
they're all fish and it's like what the
heck. Yeah, I really like ZSH, but FZF
it's really good. It's called fuzzy find
or fuzzy finder and it's basically like
a better version of control R like or
like history search on terminal.
And it also works for like finding files
on your file system. If you just type
FZF, it'll look in your local file
system and you can it's like basically
fuzzy finding, right? So, you can type
like parts of your command. You can type
like Frida and then you can type maybe
an app that you've run before or like
dash N or something and it'll fuzzy
search across the across your commands
like not just exact search like how
reverse search is.
And it's really really good.
Solid. I just added that to the notes
for the
for the description. That looks super
helpful. They've got something a little
bit similar to that with with fish by
default, but yeah, that seems seems
better.
Um
Okay. Anyways, so
Joel knows his command line flags. I do
not know my command line flags. That's
that's the the TLDR of that.
I've written a Frida script or two in my
day. Yeah, yeah, I can see it. I can see
it.
Okay, so we've got the server running.
We So, when you say dash F or dash N,
you're launching a process. So, normally
what that looks like is you are giving
it the package name.
Right, for the for the um Yeah, for
launch you give it the package name and
for attach you give it the app name.
That's also a new thing. It used to be
that it was the package name for both.
If you do Frida dash PS
space dash U again dash U for like USB
your connected device
then that will list the processes that
Frida sees and it'll show you like if
you have a running app, it'll show you
the app name, right? It won't show you
the package and then for the rest of
them it should show like the package.
So, that's kind of how you'll know.
Um but if you want to that's like one
thing that you do need to either look up
or be aware of is if you want to spawn
an app and you only know the name of the
app, you're going to have to find the
package name. That's not hard to do, but
just be aware. Yeah, no, that that's
that's gotten me recently cuz I was like
why is this Frida command not working? I
copied and pasted from the last time I
used Frida and then it was like
Yeah, okay. So, there's some
differentiation there. I love how you
are like a walking Frida documentation.
I dig that. Um
So, okay. So, we've got it running. We
run the script. Um you know, decrypts
the the uh the SSL cert pinning. Happy
day. Now we're able to, you know, use
the app. Um we can talk about custom SSL
cert pinning implementations, but um the
other thing that I want to go I want to
jump backwards a little bit. So, in this
situation, this assumes that we are
using a rooted device. Um because you
can't just have other processes hooking
into other processes if they're not
rooted, right? So, um
what about the situations, Joel, when
you cannot use a rooted device? For
whatever reason, like the app flips out
if you're on a rooted device. Um
what is your what is your approach to
that?
Yeah, so it depends on how they're doing
their checks. Typically, um we we did
mention like you can patch the APK. So,
that is an option. Um there are ways to
get Frida within a an APK through
patching. Essentially, you put the
native a Frida native library into the
app. You resign the app or you edit the
smali code to load that library, which
will be the same as launching Frida
server, but within just that process,
right? So, instead of being system-wide
Frida, it's I patched this APK to load
Frida specifically, and it has Frida,
but nothing else does. Um and then you
can
attach to it like you would with Frida
server, but it's just that single
instance of the app. Um you can do that.
Uh or you can just edit the smali code,
and you can, you know, make changes,
recompile it, resign it,
install it, run it, and that could be
your workflow. It's just a lot slower.
It's a lot more tedious.
There are definitely cases, I think most
often I would say like banking apps,
money apps. Those have the most uh
stringent type of security policies that
you have to have for device security.
So, it like is the device a secure
environment? Essentially, like uh mainly
for like protecting people's money and
identity theft and all that kind of
stuff. Just the types of stuff that you
can do through mobile banking apps and
mobile money apps nowadays are
equivalent to walking into the bank. So,
they have to be very very secure about
that type of stuff. They want to make
sure your phone's not compromised. All
that all that jazz, right? So,
those are probably where you're going to
run into a lot of these issues, and
they're going to be like complex type of
systems that are going to try and stop
you from running on a rooted device.
They might be using stuff like
attestations that are going to be
verified on the server side before you
even log in. Mm.
That is probably
going to be the trickiest situation
because attestation stuff is implemented
at like an OS system level by Google
either through the Play Integrity app
Play Integrity API or the SafetyNet
APIs. Both of those are like really hard
to get around and bypass and spoof
just because of where they're located.
They're like lower than Frida. Mm. So,
um and they're like very complex native
library driven systems that are hard to
intercept. So, it's just like it's not
an easy task to overcome.
However, generally speaking, you'll
probably be able to get around most
things with either just straight-up
Frida scripts or manually patching the
app. Yeah. That's a good point. So, just
if if it's if, for example, you know,
you run into a situation where you don't
If you run into a situation Yeah. Yeah.
Um you run into a situation where you
or you know, the app is like, "Hey,
you're rooted. Don't don't do that, you
know." Um
I don't know why my app's a cat.
Your cat is a mad cat.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Um but, you know,
then we can the first approach I'd
imagine is let's just disable that. So,
you know, you go into this the code um
in
VS VS Code if you're cool, JADX GUI if
you're not. And then um you you find the
place where that root function, you
know, that root check is being done. A
lot of times I do that via um taking the
error code and then just kind of working
backwards, figuring out what string.xml
that that is, and then, you know,
figuring out where that string.xml is
located in the actual Java code, and
then, you know, narrowing down what
function is doing this
um
this check. And then there's normally a
function that just returns a boolean
that's like
uh you know, is rooted true, is rooted
false. And then you can just override
that um with with uh Frida, and um you
know, change that false to a true or
change it to always return, you know,
false if it is rooted, you know, that
sort of thing. Right. And that in for
those of you that that are a little bit
intimidated by that task, if you look at
Joel's um uh
SSL unpinner script, um you'll see these
functions uh these these actually uh
assignments, variable assignments. I'm
going to I'm looking at the one on line
34 here. certificate
pinner.check.overload.implementation.
What he's doing there is he's he's
selected the specific certificate pinner
class on line 33 uh okhttp3.certificate
pinner. And then he's selected the check
function and selected the overload um
for that because there's multiple check
functions depending on the parameters um
that takes a string and list. And then
he's taking that implementation and
overriding it with this function that
he's defined right after there, which is
essentially just saying we we
intercepted HTTP3 or OKHTTP3, and then
um you know, we're just returning saying
everything's good, right? So, that's how
easy it is to override functions, just
arbitrary functions inside the code. Um
right.
Yeah, so the way that this check works,
typically it would throw an exception.
So, that's why you're just doing a
return. Typically, the way that it would
check is it's a void it's a void return.
It doesn't actually return anything. It
just executes, and if there's a
certificate error, it throws an
exception, which which would get caught
by whatever's calling it. So, instead,
you just exit out immediately. There's
no error, no problem. Keep going. No
error, no problem. No error, no problem.
No error, no problem. Um okay.
We're we're in a goofy mood today, man.
Um
okay. So, going going back to going back
to um the using Frida on Android without
root. Um
There's a
article that I wanted to call out that's
like my go-to article for this that I
just like I remember very vividly when I
started learning about this um this
article by a person called ikoz, i k o
z. I I love that guy. Yeah. Um and so,
let me let me pull up his Twitter as
well. I don't know if it's just ikoz.
Yeah, it's just ikoz. Um and he does an
article called Using Frida on Android
without root. Very
very apt name. Um and he walks through,
you know, the basics of how to do it,
and, you know, in detail doing exactly
what you would what you would need to
do. So, that one's great. If you really
want to understand what's going on, um
I, when I was first learning, I went
ahead and manually patched the smali
code, which is kind of kind of a tricky
process. Um but it was good to
understand what was happening. And then
ever since I have been using this tool
called objection,
um which I'll also link in the
description an article by NetSPI, n e t
s p i. Um and
let me just pull that up right here.
It's it's written by Cody Wass, um and
it's four ways to bypass Android SSL
verification and certificate pinning is
the title. Um and uh just really good
information there on how to use
objection and some other ways to get
around certificate pinning. So, I'll
link both of those excellent resources.
Um like Joel said, you probably
shouldn't have to do this too much, um
but if you do, um it's good to be able
to do it, and it allows you to get some
around some really some really tricky uh
situations. So,
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, objection is pretty good. Um
it's like I I refer to it as kind of a
multi-tool. So, like multi-tools, if
you've ever had a multi-tool, like if
it's like a the knife version of a
multi-tool, it's like, you know, it's
pretty good at a lot of things, but it's
not going to be the best knife. It's not
going to be the best pliers. It's not
going to be the best screwdriver, right?
So, that's where you're going to
want to dive into individual tools that
really specialize in the specific areas.
But, as a general all-around tool that
can do like a lot of different things,
it's really good for that. Yeah. Solid.
That makes sense. So, check out
objection if you're in that sort of
situation.
Okay. So, let me look at the doc real
quick cuz we're we're getting we're
getting long here on time. Um
Okay. So,
we have a root today Let's say Let me
give you a hypothetical. We've got a
root detection function in there. Um
did did the the flow that I described,
you know, tracing it back through the
strings and that sort of thing, did that
resonate with you? Is there any other
tips and tricks you have for like
finding where the the functions are in
the code that do the thing that you're
trying to make not happen?
Yeah, so I mean, what you described is
generally the first place I would look.
Like see is there's is there an error
being like on the screen that I can
search within the app, find a string,
find where it's referenced in the code,
trace that back, see where it's thrown,
see where what's causing this pinning,
etc., right? Trace just trace it back
from like an unknown thing.
That is probably the first thing that I
would try. If I can't get anywhere with
that, I would probably check logcat, um
Yeah, that's the other one.
adb logcat. There are a couple different
flags you can throw on logcat that will
let you filter by specific like a
specific app or a specific PID. So,
you'll only see logs for like just that
running app, which makes it a lot
cleaner and a lot easier to read and
understand what's going on.
Um I'll check logcat because logcat will
have it might have an exception thrown.
It might have an error message that's
related. Like similarly, that it might
not be shown like on the screen, but it
might be in the logcat that's showing
either a trace back or an exception or
some kind of log message that I can also
search for in the code.
Um and then if that doesn't work, I'll
start searching for generic terms. I'll
start searching for pin, pinning,
certificate,
uh maybe even like SSL or verification
or something like that and I'll just
look and see. If I still I'm not finding
anything,
uh then I'm just going to like start
digging through package files that are
related to the app. Like you know, it's
like you just got to keep going. It's
going to get grindy after a certain
point. Yeah, I imagine so. And and um
yeah, that I mean most of the time that
should get you there. The only other
time that I've kind of run into a
situation where I was like, "Ah, I
cannot find this function." Um
is, you know, sometimes those these
functions can be
da da da da da in native libraries,
right? Um so, talk to me a little bit
about this concept of native libraries
and how it makes our life more difficult
as an Android tester.
Sure. Yeah, so native libraries are
basically portions of the Android code
base that are written in native
C or C++. So, it's like
uh say you have this
hash signing or like for a legitimate
use case, it would be something that you
want to run faster than a cannon job.
Sure.
Right? Or take advantage of like native
C++ level bindings or certain C++
libraries or something like that, you
would write it into C++ and then when
you build your app, you would get out a
.so file, right? Similar to what you
have on Linux.
So, it's like a a dynamic like
linkable library.
And it gets loaded from the Java side
using system.loadLibrary
and it's
it typically the bindings within the app
within that library. So, there'll be a a
method called JNI_OnLoad.
There's a whole set of methods. They're
called JNI methods, Java Native
Interface. And basically, they define
like how JNI libraries work. So, when a
JNI when you call like
system.loadLibrary,
it will automatically call JNI_OnLoad
when it loads the JNI, right?
Okay. And so, from there, a lot of
things will happen. It'll do some uh
mapping from
function names within the C++ to
function names within the Java. So,
you'll see in the Java code, for
example, if in the Java code base,
you'll see what looks like
This is getting a little technical.
You'll see what looks like an abstract
definition Oh, really? Where it will
have functions that are listed, but they
have no bodies. And they'll be defined
as native within like you know, native
void whatever like native string, right?
a Is that a decorator in in Java? What
is that?
No, no, no. It's It's like one of the
like precursor keywords that that says
like, you know, where you put like void
or like public or static, right? It's
native, right? And so, you're saying
like this is a native function.
And in your C++, say you had
com.example.MyClass
Sure. and then you had a function called
like do something, okay?
In C++, your function would be
Java_com_example
_MyClass_DoSomething.
how it knows to associate the abstract
class to the the implementation, which
is in C++.
Correct. And the it has to have like a
similar function signature and
everything. It'll throw errors if it
doesn't. Sure.
Alternatively,
and this is where things also get
trickier is if they don't do that, they
can do it through JNI_OnLoad. There's
this thing called RegisterNatives. Mhm.
Um and this flew under the radar for me
for a while until I I I figured out what
it was. And basically, it lets you
register a native method to a specific
uh
signature. Like in the same way that you
would name it by that string, you can
say, "Oh, this string should actually be
associated with Oh, jeez. Yeah, I'm
seeing that. and call this pointer
instead, right? And so, that means that
they can obfuscate the native library to
like kingdom come. They can do whatever
they want with it. They can hide those
strings super super hard like the
signature string, for example. They can
have like custom string encoding and
decryption that
results in that string. And then all
they have to do there's, you know, one
assembly instruction in there that's
calling out and registering the natives
and pointing it to that pointer. And
you're going to have to figure out which
pointer it is or which function is
actually doing the stuff. Yeah. There
are a couple things that can help with
this. Um I'm blanking on like what they
are specifically, but there are there
are plugins for Ghidra and for IDA that
both will help map the JNI calls. So,
they have basically loaded up the JNI
header that has the offsets for like all
the structs and then it will rename the
references and say, "Oh, it's calling
onLoad here or it's calling
RegisterNatives or it's calling
GetClass." Um cuz there's like This is
also how you would, for instance, like
if you want to use a Java string class,
you have to do it through JNI native
bindings. So, you would do like GetClass
and then you would get an instance of
like a C++ pointer that points to that
class and it it, you know, it's it's
Java through C++. It's like Dude, that
is a very convoluted process there.
Okay, so I'm going to try to I'm going
to try to simplify it. Um so, you know,
normally the the normal situation is
we've got this this class this abstract
class and the function names are
appropriately named in the native
library and then it just kind of shoves
those implementations into the abstract
class just like you would do, you know,
in normal, you know, object-oriented
programming. But
Yeah, and that's the simplest case.
Yeah, and that that's pretty much the
only case that I've run into that I that
I could find. But also, I was going to
talk about this other case that I I uh
I couldn't figure So, maybe actually
that was what was happening. I should
have called you in this scenario because
I had this one time I was like, "Man, I
cannot patch this." And I actually ended
up All I needed to do was change one
letter in a header so that I could
override it instead of, you know, and I
actually ended up literally patching the
native library. I literally just opened
it up in hex editor and like searched
for the string and like replaced one of
the characters in the string and it
changed it and it it worked beautifully,
but
shout out to SpaceRaccoon for that
awesome idea.
Um but then maybe it could have been the
RegisterNatives thing that was that was
getting me there. So, that's that's
that's hella complex.
Um
I don't even know what I want to ask
here. So,
super dense. This is the thing with
native libraries is like generally,
native libraries are like
it it requires a whole separate skill
set, right? Because you have to be
familiar with assembly code, you have to
be familiar with like pointers and like
C++ and like JNI, which is like a whole
other thing. Um and so, it it does
definitely take like a lot of like extra
like effort and resources. I wouldn't
really recommend unless you need it to
like dive into all of that unless it's
something that's really interesting to
you. But it's one of those things that
I've kind of only like learned out of
necessity. Yeah.
Um and it it's like a very like complex
and it's super hard to like reverse
engineer it and like come at it the
other way from.
Solid. So, I'm looking at this thing
here. The only other thing that I wanted
to pick your brain on just on my on my
hit list here was like, okay,
um
let's say that I I've had this scenario
happen a couple times where I was like,
"Okay, I found the function I need to
override." And like for some reason it's
not letting me override it in in Frida.
Um
There's there's this thing I think you I
think I messed with you and I think we
came up with the conclusion. Let me see
if I can find this app or this Yeah,
here it is. So, what we ended up doing
was Java.perform and then we put the the
function call inside of it. And then
what I ended up doing was having to run
setInterval, which is a JavaScript
function which runs a function at a set
interval.
Periodically named. Um and and then, you
know, it would run that function again.
And then whenever that function got
defined, it would just override it,
override it, override it, override it.
Why is that happening and why why do I
have to use this setInterval function to
override the specific
function? This is a very specific
question. So, sorry about that.
about this and it was in a native
library, right? The function? Yeah, so
the reason is as I mentioned, uh native
libraries don't get initialized until
you load them. So, you have to call
system.loadLibrary in order to
initialize the native library within the
Java context.
If you don't do that and you try and
call it, it's going to be like, "I don't
know what you want me to call." Like it
doesn't know. It has to be loaded up
into memory. So, you essentially had to
wait for system.loadLibrary to be called
by the app before you could hook that
function. And that's why you had to keep
doing it on a on a timer until it got
loaded up. Once it got loaded up, then
you can hook it. Solid. Okay, so the
native library had to be loaded up and
that wasn't happening till later point
after the Frida script is running. So,
when the Frida script there's like a
little race condition there, right? When
the Frida would run, then it would be
like, "Ah, what the heck? This function
doesn't exist." And then afterwards, it
would get defined. So, when I when I
went ahead and stuck it in the the uh
setInterval and put like a try-catch
statement in there, then it would say
like, "Okay, you know, nope, not there.
Nope, not there. Yeah, yep, they loaded
it. Now I'm going to override it."
Is that accurate? Solid. Yep.
Okay, cool. Um
Well, actually that leads right quite
well into my report. You down to jump
into that now? You got anything else you
want to say on on you know, dynamic
I did I did have two things that I that
I wanted to mention. Yeah. Actually one
thing cuz I think one of them we
mentioned. I think we already talked
about proxying over USB with ADB
reverse.
in a different episode. Yeah, I've used
that all the time.
Yeah, that's been helpful. Yeah, that
Yeah, not really a dynamic hacking
thing, but certainly quite useful
especially since we talked about hacking
on physical devices. Another thing with
physical devices, and this is the other
the other thing, there's a tool that was
made by Genymotion uh or Genymobile, I
guess is the company. It's called uh
scrcpy,
um and it's basically just Um and it's
basically just a a tool that lets you
display your Android like a physical
device screen you just plug it in over
USB and you can view and control screen
on your computer. So you don't have to
like pick up your phone and stuff. It
also does like clipboard transferring
which is super nice. You can just like
click and drag stuff. It has the
buttons. It's like it's great. It's like
in between Android emulator but physical
device makes it a lot easier for doing a
lot of testing.
Dude,
for those of you listening on the
podcast I'm just sitting here with my
jaw dropped right now. This is super
cool. So is this
Yeah, super awesome.
Like
it just takes it just mirrors the screen
onto your computer and lets you
Dude, that's so helpful. Oh my gosh. And
and is it hard to set up? I mean can I
just use this with air like the the
Android studio? I don't have to use like
Jenny mobile's thing do I? No no no.
It's like it's a fully separate package.
They even have here you can get it with
apt. There you go.
No way. Really? What what it Oh my gosh.
Apt installs scrcpy. Yeah.
Screen copy I guess is what it it's
short for. But yeah on Mac you can use
brew.
They have install docs on in the read me
on their on the repo. But yeah it's a
super useful tool. I I use that like
nine times out of 10 when I'm using a
physical device just cuz it's a pain to
have to like pick it up and
have it connected somewhere that I can
touch the screen and all that kind of
stuff and all that copy pasting and all
that whatever. Dude, that is a game
changer right there. I'm installing that
right now.
Oh my gosh. That's going to be real
cool. Okay, I I'm putting that in the
show notes. Let me let me get that. Any
of you guys who do mobile hacking on a
general or on a normal basis that is a
you got it nice you beat me to it.
That is a game changer right there.
Dang it Joel, why didn't you tell me
about that before man? This is
I was thinking about it but we had
already moved on when we were talking
about the physical versus emulator thing
and we moved on to jadx and I was like
I'll just write this down and
it was like on my sticky note till the
end. I'm glad I I checked in with you
again rather than just jumping right
into the reports cuz that would have
missed out on that juicy tidbit.
Um
Yeah, so all right. So ADB reverse
that's in episode six
and then you know this SCR copy Yeah,
screen copy. Nice. To to display your
physical device on your on your host.
More bangers from Joel guys. Freak I
love that. Okay.
All right, so let me jump into the
reports for the day. I was looking on
hackerone activity stuff trying to find
you know a report that we could kind of
talk through with Frida but there's
pretty much nothing.
Which was really surprising to me.
Yeah, it's really interesting. I think
part of it is that Frida scripts are
kind of like special secret sauce a lot
of the time. A lot of people
either they have their own script suites
or maybe they over time they they have
like
figured something out and they don't
want to just put it in like code
basically that anybody can download and
know like oh this is how you do that.
So I tried to push away from a lot of
that like by publishing my cert pinning
script and that kind of stuff.
That's kind of like a big long standing
problem in my opinion with most of like
the mobile hacking space is that a lot
of it is like secret knowledge that
people have like built up over time and
they don't really talk about it. They
just like show the cool results which is
really cool but
it doesn't really help build like a
strong mobile security community that
can like expand and other people can
learn all that kind of stuff. So I try
to be as public as I can about a lot of
this stuff. Yeah dude, I definitely
appreciate that. So thanks for for
sharing the sauce there.
Um
Let me just talk through this report
really quickly.
So this one was a little bit interesting
one. This is a high
and this is an ATO on a specific service
that I can't name but there was this
service where several people would come
together and they would help provide
care for another individual. Um and
the way that this
service sort of worked is um
well it it was primarily done through an
app and that app was using SSL pinning
but wasn't just using any SSL pinning.
It was using custom SSL pinning which is
actually we didn't get super much into
that so I'm glad we have this report so
we can talk through it.
So it's using
you know I fired up Frida
through Joel's universal
you know unpin at it and it it wasn't
allowing me to see the traffic so I was
still seeing and one of the ways you can
tell that you're you're not seeing the
traffic is if you go to burp and you go
to the let me just pop burp open right
now. Yeah, if you go to dashboard and
you go to event log down there it'll say
client failed to negotiate a TLS
connection
and that will tell you that you know
cert pinning is is sort of in place
and and you also see some stuff in the
app as well.
Um
And so
the
situation here was that they had a
custom cert pinning implementation and
um
there was a function that I'm trying to
I'm trying to say it without without
actually giving away too much of
details. Anyway, there's there's a
function called TLS config. Um and
it was inside of or there's a class
called TLS config inside of that was a a
function called set verify server. And
this was you know so this is a classic
and it returned a boolean right? So this
is this is perfect for just kind of what
we were talking about. It's just a it's
a simple simple fix. You just find that
class and find that function and then
you just overwrite that function with
your own implementation that returns
false. Now
here is some big some big brain tips
okay? Um and this is one of the reasons
I I forgot about this before.
This is one of the reasons why I do use
jadx GUI as a as my
you know GUI of choice for auditing
Android apps.
Inside of jadx GUI you can right click
on a function and hit copy as Frida
snippet.
And this will literally take the the
function class take everything just give
you this beautiful Frida snippet and
then you can just drop it right into a
script and run it and it will overwrite
that function and give you like logs
with that function when that function
gets called.
Sorry.
That is pretty neat. That's that's
pretty freaking cool right? So I I did
that and put that in there and I was
seeing that it okay was getting called
and then I just went ahead and and
overwrote it with um
uh you know
set false set false. Um so that allowed
me to see the traffic for the specific
service which was under under
audited because of this
you know custom SSL pinning. And
when I went into that that traffic I saw
what one of the functions there was an
impersonate function where these you
know group of people can help this other
person do their job
by you know impersonating and like
taking over their um you know screen or
whatever and and doing the action for
them. Um whenever you see stuff like
that you should you should be you should
be hearing the ching from the bounties
because that is that is normally very
very hard to implement properly. And um
I was hoping that I could potentially
just put in
you know any of users ID and it would
just let me you know impersonate that
user. Wasn't the case but it did allow
me to put in the ID of somebody on my
like care team
and then get the get the access token
for them. So the other people that are
kind of working in the same scenario as
me to help you know
this person do their job this other
person do their job I could take over
their accounts. So then we got arbitrary
account takeover in that in that way on
those accounts and that was that
resulted in a in a high vulnerability
and I would never have found it if I
hadn't gone through that those loops to
get rid of that SSL cert pinning and I
and I have to say
like sometimes it can feel really like I
just spent like five hours you know
trying to bypass SSL pinning and stuff
like that but just like we talk about
all the time with like getting access to
scope or paying the extra 50 bucks to
get the premium feature or you know
getting access to scope that other
attackers aren't willing to go through
the effort to get access to or aren't
willing to pay the money to get access
to that almost always produces amazing
results. So
taking it a little bit further bypassing
that custom SSL pinning implementation
bypassing that root detection can often
land you some pretty sick bounties even
in the HTTP realm. It doesn't
necessarily have to be some crazy mobile
bug but you know it can also just be an
HTTP you know rest API bug as well.
Yeah, 100% a lot of that security
through obscurity stuff happens in the
mobile space just cuz people don't look
at mobile and people don't understand
mobile and people don't know how to get
past some of the basic security measures
that exist on mobile like cert pinning
and as a result they just put a lot of
really crazy stuff behind that.
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. So that's the
that's the report I had.
You got one you want to talk about Joel?
Yeah, so this is this is actually my
first ever bug. This is the first ever
report I created on hackerone. Yeah,
this is this was at the H1702 2017 my
first live hacking event my first bug
bounty anything and
one of the targets was Uber.
And they were like uh
they were one of they had put up a
challenge that they had like a specific
couple of challenges and one of the
challenges was to bypass
the jailbreak detection on their driver
app. Nice. I was like oh I can
definitely do that. I use Frida all the
time. Like I could just hook a couple
methods and so I spent all night like I
I hadn't done any like hacking ahead of
time or anything like cuz I I was like
super out of the loop on all this stuff
so
I just like sat down and I I just like
dug into it and I wrote up this like
crazy long Frida script that hooked a
bunch of different things and yeah I
bypassed it and I actually got to do a
show and tell for that.
Again it was my my first live hacking
event. I was like I I had no idea what
was even going on. I was like Yeah. so
out of it. I was so like, what is all
this? Who Who is this Franz Rosen guy?
Dude, well, congrats cuz that's I mean,
getting to do a show in Tel Aviv your
first Live Hack event is nuts. Um that's
how you can tell you got
some serious, you know, you're in the
right place. Um
but yeah, I will say I have seen a
couple challenges like that where people
will put like, you know, if they have a
mobile app and scope they're like, "Hey,
if you can bypass our root detection,
we'll give you, you know, a medium or
something like that." And I always eat
those up, man. Like I I I have I'll just
pull up my
I've got more than this one. I've I have
I've got three or four
highs that I've gotten from from
bypassing that type of stuff because
Yeah, most of the time the problem is
that the the checks are on the client
side, right? So like they're very
trusting towards what the client is
sending and they just assume that the
stuff that if the client has gotten that
data, that it's legitimate. And you can
either just feed in fake data to the
client or you can bypass those checks
and make it look legitimate.
Um and then the server will trust a lot
of that stuff and you've already proven
an impact.
Wow, that's crazy. Yeah, so I I've got a
couple of of those. I have never been
paid more than a medium for it. Um but
apparently there's highs out there to be
gained and like like Joe said, there's
pretty much, you know, it's it's it's
almost always possible, right? You know,
cuz there's there's um all of this code
that's running
on the device is in your control if
you're running on a rooted device.
Um
so you should be able to theoretically
go in there, hook the right functions,
return the right values, and bypass the
whole thing. So definitely something to
be on the lookout for there.
Yeah.
Cool.
I think that was it for me. This was a
long episode. I I know there was a lot
of data condensed in here. Um
but yeah, I I hope that it was helpful.
Yeah, for sure, man. It always is. And
um
yeah, I'm I'm looking through here. I
think we hit most everything, so that's
good. We definitely We still have so
much more to cover in mobile, so
there'll definitely be more mobile
episodes to come and and uh it seems
like you guys really enjoyed the last
one. Um so yeah, we'll definitely keep
those keep those coming at a at a pace
where you can take some time, digest all
the wisdom that that Joel has imparted
to us.
Um
and yeah, become become better mobile
hackers, so
Is that the pod?
I think that's the pod. All right.
Peace.